Bernardo Botella

DEV ENGINEER

http://www.bernardobotella.com (http://www.bernardobotella.com)

contacto@bernardobotella.com (mailto:contacto@bernardobotella.com)

+34 676 471530

↑ C/ Sagasta Nº 19 46740, Carcaixent, Spain, ES



(http://twitter.com/bbotella)





New technologies passionate with experience in research World and infinite eagerness. I offer high problem solving skills, imaginative and reliable solutions and global vision and an approachable attitude. I am an expert in innovation, entrepreneurship and technology execution, combined with a high level of technical insight, and a firmly believer on technologies to be the way human lives will improve in the future.



WORK EXPERIENCE

Scrapinghub

Engineer 2015-04-01 - 2016-04-01 http://www.scrapinghub.com (http://www.scrapinghub.com)

Dealing with platform problems. Managing big amounts of data, and crawling the web

• Developing platforms that matter

Mindrop

Information Retrieval Engineer

2014-02-01 - 2015-04-01

http://www.mindrop.com (http://www.mindrop.com)

I deployed and managed an information retrieval cluster, and a platform to crawl thousands of webs and indentify millions of documents.

Crawl and Search

Universitat Politécnica de Valéncia (UPV)

Researcher

2012-09-01 - 2015-02-01

http://www.upv.es (http://www.upv.es)

Working hard with Arduino and Android devices. Internet of things related research and developments.

Internet of things

Ereadme

CEO

2010-07-01 - 2012-09-01

I created and lead a startup in the monitoring services space, designing and deploying systems to control physical variables such as temperature and electrical consumption and act according to context.

Monitoring context

Hilton Valencia

Information Systems Manager

2008-06-01 - 2010-07-01

http://www.hilton.com (http://www.hilton.com)

In charge of the hotel IT department, managing budgets and security policies and design, and leading a team of two people to assure a high system availability and

performance.

• Sysadmin



EDUCATION

Universitat Politécnica de València (UPV)

Computer engineer

Bachelor

2003-09-01 - 2008-07-01

UCV

Business

Master in Business Administration

2008-07-01 - 2009-11-01



Python	Java	С	Solr
Master	Master	Medium	Master
python	• java	• C	searchinformation retrieval



English

Fluent speaker

Spanish

Native speaker

Catalan

Native speaker



INTERESTS

Photography

Mathematics